Prabhas Mondal

Gachibowli, Hyderabad, Telangana mondalp.dgp19@gmail.com +919679049540

Summary

Java Developer with 4 years of experience in application development, enhancement of the framework, and API designing using JAVA/J2EE, Spring, Hibernate, JSP, MySQL & ExtJS. Have experience in working with XML, JSON, REST APIs & Regex. Worked on Analytics where we develop highly interactive charts and dashboards, to help end user understand the data easily. Also, worked with a large team of developers to maintain and improve company projects, development and enhancement of features and fulfill client requirements. Seeking to secure a challenging position as a Java or Back-end Developer.

Skills

JAVA, Hibernate, Spring, JDBC, Git, Data Structure and Algorithms, MySQL, DBMS

Experience

Software Engineer

HighRadius • Hyderabad, Telangana 06/2021 - Present

- Working on the development and enhancement of the HighRadius, Collections application using Java, Spring, Hibernate, ExtJS, and MySQL.
- · Analyze, design, develop, the new and existing functionality in the product.
- I have developed a new feature i.e. Task Management system where product owners can create tasks and assigned it to owners from across product on client side. A cross-product Task Management system.
- · Recently I took full ownership of Multi-Language in the Application for Collections Product.
- · Worked on core items of all products, improving the application usability where user is login in with different time zones.
- · Analyzed user needs and proposed design software solutions to meet them.
- · Resolved bugs, data issues and errors through close collaboration with the quality assurance team. Implemented
- · enhancement requests from the clients.
- · Created documentation covering existing processes, feature requests, and system reporting tools.
- Developed, tested, debugged, and documented software features and enhancements.
- · Worked within an agile scrum team, contributing to 100% continuous improvement.

Receivable Analyst

HighRadius • Bhubaneshwar, Odisha 06/2020 - 05/2021

- Experience working with MySQL and for developing highly interactive charts and dashboards, to help end user understand the data easily.
- Developed a newly formulated interactive TimeLine charts Days Deduction Outstanding for Deduction product.
- · Worked on improving the performance of existing charts, where performance improved by almost 70%.
- · Developed design documents, user guides, maintenance documents, project documentation, and release documents.

Product and Engineering Intern

HighRadius • Bhubaneshwar, Odisha

04/2020 - 06/2020

Designed an Al enabled B2B Invoice Management Application using Database Management (SQL), Exploratory Data
Analysis (Python), Application of Machine Learning Models for Predictive Modelling, DialogFlow for chatbot design and
React for the UI development.

Education

B.Tech.

Kalinga Institute of Industrial Technology (KIIT) • Bhubaneshwar, Odisha 06/2017 - 05/2021

- · Majored in Computer Science and Engineering
- Graduated with 9.09 CGPA

Certifications

· Android App Development Certification (06/2019) - Globesyn Finishing School, Kolkata, West Bengal

Personal Projects

- Educational Website A full-fledged website for an educational institute with frontend and backend development and maintenance single handedly. https://iteduhub.netlify.com/
- OS Processes Scheduler An Android project on OS Scheduling using single-core CPU and infinite I/O resources.
- Covid-19 India Tracker Developed a website for keeping a track of the COVID 19 in India single handedly. https://india-covid19tracker.netlify.app/
- Emergency App Developed an app for the accident victims providing emergency medical services. This can also be used for senior citizen and pregnant women.

Portfolios, Profiles

- https://pmondalg8.netlify.app/
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/prabhas-mondal-28314b16b/
- https://github.com/pmondal98

Languages

English, Hindi, Bengali

Interests

Innovations & Technology, Website Development, Android Development